Hi, I'm Mike. I'm sitting down with Clark and Pat. This is Pat, this is Clark, from Ankle Bracket. Ankle Bracket is a user group up here in the northwest suburbs, and actually we just came back from a meeting. So, Pat, Clark, can you tell me a little bit about Ankle Bracket and what you guys are doing?
Hello, Pat. Ankle Bracket is for you guys and gals, I guess, that was why we all are hacking some code.
Speak up?
Yes.
Is it not loud enough?
Speaking up, we're in a bar and this is what we do after Ankle Bracket.
So, what is Ankle Bracket? What did we just do today?
So, we've tried to form together a number of web developers like yourself to come and meet once a month and take a topic and just code it. Somewhat unstructured/structured, so I haven't talked about web sockets. We kind of kicked it off by talking about it, formed up into pairs, pop, different lines. We just started coding and then kind of revisited back to the end. Some people switched around and kind of switched around a little bit.
Yeah.
Might kind of bounce around with new groups. But this is kind of the hands-on of user groups. Unlike most UGtastic interviews, I actually participated in the user group today and I'd say one of the things I liked was that we had a topic and then it was kind of like, some people worked on Donet stuff, some people worked on Jasmine and Node, some people, while I was working on Pusher with Ruby. It's all front-end web stuff, no balance around other than front-end web stuff.
So, how long have you been doing in the back of business? Is this the same or the third year?
About three hours. Yeah, yeah.
So this was the first meeting?
This was the first meeting.
Okay. Yeah. So, what did you guys learn?
I know you've been involved quite a bit with the user group community in Chicago. You still are a depth evangelist. I'd like to talk about that.
Yeah.
So, you know, obviously you were able to bring a lot of what you've experienced going through so many groups.
Why this? Yeah, why this? Why did you decide on this form?
Get away from the user group experience. Yeah, I mean, something different.
Yeah. I think we said it in this kind of slide before, right?
We all sit at home and coat. We all learn. And that's usually by ourselves.
Yeah.
I work alone a lot of times. I work alone a lot of times. I think getting experiences from different people on how they perceive something or do something or use it differently or ask them a question, only further advances what you learn.
So, getting hands-on and being able to be with my friends, I think is even better, right? Yeah.
And that's what tonight was about. Hopefully, as time goes on, the source repository that we're all hopefully forking and pulling back into, we can grow a set of assets that, you know, when you walk away and you say, "Oh, well, we were doing this WebSocket thing.
I forgot, right?
I haven't been using it for a month or two, so it's kind of falling out of my brain. " But I know, hey, I can go to angle bracket on GitHub and I can just go grab that, and I should be able to refresh myself from where I was at. And oh, by the way, pep did this thing in WebSocket. Oh, that looked really cool. Mark did this thing and then did that thing. Maybe I'll look across all three of them somehow.
So, that's kind of the point of it, right?
So, kind of you want to build up a body of knowledge. You want to use these groups more to help, not just learn together, but also build something that people can go back and use to get them to be cool. I think one of the pettiest events is you want to be selfish. But the point is that being selfish is what you want to learn at the music. So, if you want to learn something, you can take that to the meeting and say, "I want to learn this," and find someone else who wants to learn it, too.
And we went around and asked, "What do you want to get out tonight?
This is your two hours that you spend away with your kids or your whatever. " And then you should walk away with something that you want to learn and find something that has similar interests to you. And, you know, like even with the Pusher, for me, it's something I'm working on a side project and it's a low priority for me.
Normally, when I sit down and think, "What do I have to do on this project? " Being able to sit down for this two hours and be like, "Well, what seconds is it, Dean?
Let's dig up from the back in the back lawn and bring it up. " It's not an excuse to do that. So, that was a lot of fun. And someone might have experience with Pusher next time we go there.
At least, probably someone that makes that experience with something else, right? Yeah.
Like I know for you.
I mean, do you want to struggle on that alone? Yeah.
I'm going to think of that.
Yeah.
Be able to struggle some other time.
I mean, we had guys with Pusher, Jasmine, Node, SignalR, . NET, Ruby. I tried to get Node expected running, failing miserably.
Yeah.
We had 15 people maybe, 10 people.
That's a pretty broad breadth of technology.
Yeah.
I was impressed. Level of participation was pretty amazing. Well, it looks like you're off to an auspicious start. So, anyway, thanks Clark, thanks Pat. Talk to you guys later. I was impressed. The level of participation was pretty good. Well, it looks like you're off to an auspicious start. So anyway, thanks Clark, thanks Pat. Talk to you guys later.